

Prince Raj

Full-Stack Developer

Full Stack Developer with 2 years of experience in developing, testing, and deploying web applications. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React on the front-end, and Node.js and Express on back-end. Additionally, familiar with Azure DevOps.

praj.nitskm@gmail.com



7091626749



WFH

Bengaluru, India



in linkedin.com/in/iamprinceraj

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer LTIMindtree

12/2021 - 12/2023

Insurance Project

- Created Portal for Customer Dashboard
- Developed UI for Statement generation
- Added MFA in Authentication/Authorization
- Integrated real-time chat in existing product
- Involved in Unit Testing

Intern

Burning Glass Technologies

01/2021 - 04/2021

LENS on AWS

- Deployed the LENS Xray(A Burning Glass Technologies Product) on AWS EC2
- Created a CI/CD pipeline using Teamcity to automate the manual creation of AMI

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology

National Institute of Technology, Sikkim

07/2017 - 07/2021 7.27 GPA

Higher Secondary Certificate

K.D.S. College Gogri, Khagaria

2013 - 2014 74.0%

Senior Secondary Certificate Sri Banarsi High School, Khagaria

2012 - 2013 79.8%

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

BlogVista (01/2024 - 01/2024)

BlogVista is a web application designed to help users manage and organize their collection of blogs. The app allows users to store, categorize, rate, and summarize blogs based on their reading experience.

Chat Application

Built a Chat Application using Node.js, where a user can enter a room and start real time communication with other users in the room.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Cross-Functional Collaboration

Collaborated seamlessly with UI/UX team and testing team to deliver user friendly and defect free product.

Agile Development Practices

Adopted and excelled in Agile development practices, participating in sprint planning, daily stand-ups and tracking daily tasks and component wise User Story & Features on Azure Board

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Reading Blogs

Continuous Learning